Lucas Pose Merani

Av. Echeñique 5819, #902. RM, Chile (+56) 98188 7251 posemerani@gmail.com 18.396.822-K github.com/lfpose

Available immediately for remote work in part-time or full-time modalities.

Software Engineer with 6+ years of experience working in web development. Experience developing software for Human Resources, leading developer teams and working hand in hand with experts in areas such as payrolls, workplace education, graphic design, and sales.

As a professional, I keep up to date with modern technologies in software and web in particular. I have a good computer science background and as a professional software engineer I aim to create correct, efficient, maintainable and legible code.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Freelance / Independent

Santiago, RM

April 2022 - Now

Fullstack web development, web design for various clients.

(React, TailwindCSS, TypeScript, NextJS, NPM, Git)

CampusHR

Santiago, RM

Chief Technology Officer / Co-founder

June 2019 - March 2022

- Tech lead in web application CampusHR. Human Resources software with modules for payroll calculation, file management, voucher generation, reports, climate surveys, performance surveys, employee portal and more.
- Tasks involved gathering of requirements, team management, full stack web development, choosing technologies, managing tools for team members and source code management, architecture and infrastructure design, testing, QA, sales meetings, training users, and more.
- Technologies: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, NodeJs, NPM, React, Express, TailwindUI, MySQL, Sequelize, Prisma, Git, Docker, Ubuntu, GraphQL, Apollo, Mocha, Chai and multiple other **NPM libraries.** Designed with a microservice architecture utilizing **Docker** and Redis for coordination.

CampusChile Santiago, RM

February 2016 - March 2022

Chief Technology Officer

- Creation and management of multiple *Moodle* apps for the administration and storage of students, courses, qualifications, reports and other data related to educational training services.
- Plugin development for Moodle, theme customization and other modifications in the source code. (PHP, JavaScript, HTML, CSS)
- Maintenance and creation of multiple Linux Ubuntu servers, utilizing PaaS DigitalOcean for multiple web hosting purposes, such as websites, files, images and databases. Operated from the terminal via SSH. DNS configuration. (Bash, Apache, Nginx, SSH, tmux, vim, LetsEncrypt)
- Creation of educational content, presentations and websites. Learning games, knowledge tests and more. Created with web technologies (Javascript, React, Redux) as well as software such as Adobe Captivate, HP5 and Genially.

- Audio, video, graphic and photography editing for educational content. (Adobe Premiere, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, Audacity, Sketch)
- Maintenance and configuration of open source web app *Moodle Mobile*. (Android, Ionic, Cordova.)
- Additional web development for landing pages, information gathering and knowledge verification. (React, Vercel. Ruby On Rails, Ubuntu, Apache, TailwindUI)

Sigma Construcciones LTDA.

Santiago, RM

Developer (Internship)

July 2015 - Septembre 2015

- Development of a web tool for managing meetings in company intranet.
- Dynamic web page with server communication without the use of frameworks.
- Technologies: PHP, Javascript, jQuery, Html, CSS, SQL.

EDUCATION

Pontifical Catholic University of Chile

Santiago, RM

Computer Science Engineer

2022

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

- Native spanish
- Fluent English
 - o YLE Flyers (2003), PET (2007), FCE (2011), TOEFL iBT 102/120 (2013)
- Intermediate skills in Microsoft Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Adobe Premiere, Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, Figma, Sketch, Audacity, Slack, Jira.
- Experience with web technologies such as Javascript, Typescript, React, Ubuntu, Apache, Nginx, SSH, BASH, GIT, Prisma, Sequelize, MySQL, NPM, Github Package Manager, Node, Docker, NextJS, Ruby On Rails, Python, CSS, LESS, TailwindUI, MaterialUI, Webpack, ExpressJS, GraphQL, Apollo, Mocha, Chai.
- Additional work:
 - o https://atlas-sphere.vercel.app/
 - o https://climatecare.s-o-f-t.agency/2019/